College of Humanities and Social Sciences Records 1913-1999 1960-1989
Carnegie Mellon University
- College of Humanities and Social Science, This series is arranged in the following Subseries: History of the College of HSS Annual Reports Councils Plans Budget/Financial Matters Student Information Administrative Information Faculty Centers Surveys/Studies Correspondence Publications Newsclipping
  - Faculty
    - Faculty--Memoranda, 1966-1971
    - Faculty--Memoranda, 1988-1989, 1993
    - Faculty--Teaching and Research in Humanities and Social Sciences, 1986
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--"Teacher Education at Carnegie Institute of Technology", 1961, 1962
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--"Report on the Re-Evaluation of the Teacher Education Program at Carnegie Institute of Technology", 1963
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--Correspondence, 1961-1964
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--Memoranda, 1956-1964
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--"Proposal for the Training of Part-Time Teachers", date unknown
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--"Curriculum Development and Teacher Education", date unknown
    - Faculty--Teacher Education--Flyers, date unknown
  - Centers
    - Communication Design Center--"CDC Newsletter", 1983-1987
    - Communication Design Center--CDC Technical Report Series, date unknown
    - Communication Design Center--General Correspondence, 1983, 1984, 1985
    - Communication Skills Center--Memoranda, 1978
    - Education Center--Press Releases, 1966-1974, 1979, 1980
    - Education Center--Articles, 1977, 1979
    - Education Center--Support Requests to Carnegie Corporation, 1966
    - Education Center--Annual Report, 1966-1967
    - Study Skills Center--Progress Report, 1968
    - Teaching Aids Center--Guide, date unknown
    - University Teaching Center--"Trainer of Teaching Trainers" Project, 1969-1971
    - University Teaching Center--TTT Project--"Community Experiences List", January 1970
    - University Teaching Center--Graduate Teaching Assistant Workshop, 1981
    - University Teaching Center--Center ESL Program, 1983, 1984, 1987
    - University Teaching Center--"A Handbook for Teaching Fellows, Teaching Assistants, and Course Assistants at Carnegie-Mellon University", 1983
    - University Teaching Center--"About Teaching at Carnegie-Mellon University", 1984
    - University Teaching Center--"Communiques About Teaching", 1991
    - University Teaching Center--Budget Proposal, 1983
    - University Teaching Center--Seminar on Sexism, 1989
    - University Teaching Center--General Correspondence, 1981-1986
    - University Teaching Center--General Correspondence, 1983
    - University Teaching Center--General Correspondence, 1984-1985
    - University Teaching Center--Pamphlets, 1962-1963
    - University Teaching Center--Impact Newsletter, 1980
    - University Teaching Center--UTC Newsletter--vol. 1, Nos. 1-3, 1983
    - University Teaching Center--"Conducting Seminars: A Set of Case Studies", date unknown
    - University Teaching Center--"Evaluating Faculty Performance", date unknown
    - University Teaching Center--"Planning a Course and Preparing a Syllabus", date unknown
    - University Teaching Center--"Surviving, Enjoying, and Flourishing at Carnegie-Mellon University", date unknown
    - University Teaching Center--Memoranda, 1981, 1984, 1985
  - Surveys and Studies
    - Dean’s Office--Security Statistics, 1983-1984
    - Study--Data--Enrollment vs. Teaching, 1980
    - Study--HSS Benchmark Data, 1975-1986
    - Study--Grade Inflation--3.0, 1988
    - Study--Student/Faculty Statistics, 1974-1980
    - Survey--Alumni Careers, 1977
    - Survey--Alumni Careers, 1977[2]
    - Survey--Alumni Careers, 1977[3]
    - Survey--Benchmark--General, 1986
    - Survey--Report--"Cultural Diversity and Character Change at Carnegie Tech", 1965
    - Survey--Report--"Cultural Diversity and Character Change at Carnegie Tech", 1965[2]
    - Survey--Report--Grade Inflation Study Version 3.0, 1988
    - Survey--Report--Grade Inflation Study 2.0, 1987
    - Survey--Summary--Units Taught by Department, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--English, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--History, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--Philosophy, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--Psychology, Fall 1983-Spring 1987=
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--Social to Decision Sciences, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--Economics, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--Units Taught by Department--Statistics, Fall 1983-Spring 1987
    - Survey--Data--HSS Compared to CIT, MCS, CFA--Index, 1986
    - Survey--Data--Comparison of Undergraduate Colleges, 1981-1986
    - Survey--Data--Top 6 Departments, 1985-1986
    - Survey--Data--Comparison of Colleges--HSS v. GSIA, SUPA, CS, 1981-1986
    - Survey--Data--CMU Departments Ranked by Research Expenditures--1985-1986
    - Survey--Data--Statistics from Lucy Rich, 1984-1985
    - Survey--Benchmark Data, 1970-1980
    - Survey--Data--Operating Statistics--Lucy Rich, 1978-1983
    - Survey--Data--Operating Statistics, 1981-1983
    - Survey--Grade Study Document Draft, 1987
    - Survey--Grade Study Raw Data, 1987
    - Survey--Grade Inflation Study--Disks--3.5, 1987-1988
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence--Crecine, John, 1980-1986
    - Correspondence--Cyert, Richard, 1982-1986
    - Correspondence--Cyert, Richard, 1987
    - Correspondence--Cyert, Richard, 1988
    - Correspondence--Cyert, Richard, 1989
    - Correspondence--Fagerhaugh, 1959
    - Correspondence--Eddy, William, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Feinberg, Stephen, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Keisler, Charles, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Korn, James, 1968
    - Correspondence--Penna, Anthony, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Sholar, William, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Steinberg, Erwin, 1966-1969
    - Correspondence--Van Horn, Richard, date unknown
    - Correspondence--Pittsburgh Symphony Special Concert Series, October 1988
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous, 1956-1957
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous, 1998
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous, 1999
  - Publications
    - Carnegie Review, April 1970
    - "An Excellent Choice", 1985
    - "Professional Choices in HSS", 1986
    - "Faculty Teaching and Research in Humanities and Social Sciences", 1986
    - Focus, 1974
    - Promotional Brochures, date unknown
    - Bowman, Mary Jean--"Expectations, Uncertainty, and Business Behavior", 1958
    - Covey, Preston, et al.--"The Mac II Workstation Initiative", 1988
    - "Communications Design: An Interdisciplinary Doctorate in Document Design", date unknown
    - "Language, Culture, and the Arts", date unknown
    - HSS Bulletin, 1970
    - HSS Bulletin, 1971
    - HSS News, July-December 1985
    - HSS News, 1987-1994
    - "As Others See HSS", 1985-1987
    - "The Sloping Halls Review; Vol. II", 1995
    - "The Latest on Computing in the College of Humanities and Social Sciences", 1992
    - Pamphlets, date unknown
    - Posters--Faculty Fellowships in the Humanities for Computer Assisted College Instruction, date unknown
  - Newsclippings
    - Newsclippings, 1977
    - Newsclippings, 1978
    - Newsclippings, 1980
    - Newsclippings, 1981
    - Newsclippings, 1982
    - Newsclippings, 1982[2]
    - Newsclippings, 1983
    - Newsclippings, 1984
    - Newsclippings, date unknown
    - Newsclippings, 1989
    - Newsclippings, 1989[2]
    - Newsclippings, 1989[3]
  - Curriculum
    - Slides--Presentations--Crecine, date unknown
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1922-1928
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1929-1936
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1936-1939
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1939-1940
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1941-1944
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1945-1946
    - Curriculum Committee--Minutes, 1947-1948
    - Core Curriculum--Synopsis, date unknown
    - Core Curriculum--Synopsis, date unknown[2]
    - Metacurriculum, 1970
    - Core Curriculum--Teaching Series, date unknown
    - Core Curriculum--Requirements, date unknown
    - Core Curriculum--Syllabi, 1978
    - Core Curriculum--Syllabi, 1980
    - Core Curriculum--Courses Taught, 1964
    - Core Curriculum--Courses for Non-HSS Students, 1968
    - Core Curriculum--"University Core: Status and Prospectus", 1986
    - Core Curriculum--Mac II Initiative, 1990
    - Core Curriculum--"Design and Implementation of an Undergraduate Liberal-Professional Curriculum", 1977
    - Core Curriculum--"Liberal-Professional Curriculum", date unknown
    - Core Curriculum--Professional Choices in HSS, 1980
    - Core Curriculum--"Liberal/Professional Education at Carnegie Mellon University", date unknown
    - Core Curriculum--Articles, Newsclippings, 1978-1981
    - Core Curriculum--Correspondence, 1978
    - Core Curriculum--Correspondence, 1980
    - Core Curriculum--Correspondence, 1984-1986
    - Core Curriculum--Correspondence, 1987
    - Humanities Symposium, 1981
    - Humanities Research, 1981
  - Graduate Program
    - Graduate Programs--Requirements, 1978-1982
    - Graduate Programs--Community College Faculty Development, 1974-1976
    - Graduate Programs--Doctor of Arts Graduates, 1968-1976
    - Graduate Programs--General Review, 1980-1981
    - Graduate Programs--Doctor of Arts, 1974-1982
    - Graduate Programs--English, History, and the Natural Sciences, date unknown
    - Graduate Programs--Humanities, 1969
  - Special Programs
    - Advanced Placement Program--Reports, 1960-1962
    - Advanced Placement Program--Miscellaneous, 1959, 1962, 1963
    - Brochure--Carnegie Recognition Award Program, 1988
    - Essay Contest, 1945, 1946, 1948, 1950
    - European Studies Program--Memo, 1983
    - Falk Lectures, 1958
    - Falk Lectures, 1959
    - Falk Lectures, 1960
    - Falk Lectures, 1961
    - Falk Lectures, 1962
    - Falk Lectures, 1963
    - Falk Lectures, 1964
    - Falk Lectures, 1965
    - Falk Lectures, 1966
    - Falk Lectures, 1966[2]
    - Falk Lectures, 1967
    - Falk Lectures, 1968
    - Falk Lectures--Funding, 1958-1960
    - Falk Lectures--Funding, 1961-1962
    - Falk Lectures--Advertisement, date unkown
    - Freshman Parent’s Day, 1982
    - Allen Ginsberg Poetry Readings, 1994
    - Greenbrier Presentation--"Liberal Professional Education", 1981
    - Greenbrier Program, 1983
    - Greenbrier Presentation, 1983
    - Homecoming, 1981, 1984
    - Homecoming, 1984
    - Honors Symposium Program, 1990-1992
    - Medieval Semester, 1972
    - Poetry on the Buses--Program, 1977-1978
    - Poetry on the Buses--Remarks and Correspondence, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Poets and Writers Newsletter, 1976
    - Poetry on the Buses--Annual Report, 1977-1978
    - Poetry on the Buses--Remarks by Joan A. Mondale, Dept. of Transportation, 1977
    - Poetry on the Buses--Remarks by National Endowment for the Arts Chairman, Nancy Hanks, 1977
    - Poetry on the Buses--Remarks by K. P. Service, 1978
    - Poetry on the Buses--Newsclippings, 1975-1977
    - Poetry on the Buses--Sponsors, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Proposal for Department of Transportation, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Destinations, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Examples of Work, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Article, March 1978
    - Robotics, 1980-1981
    - Social Relations--Program, 1941-1943
    - Social Relations--Program, 1953-1965
    - Social Relations--Electives, 1960
    - Traveling Seminar, 1956
    - Study Abroad--Centre de Tours, date unknown
    - Women’s Information Network, 1993-1994
    - Women’s Information Network, 1993-1994[2]
    - Women’s Information Network--Accounting, 1994
- Departments, This series is arranged in the following Subseries by Department: Economics English History Philosophy Modern Languages Physical Education Political Science Psychology Social Science Statistics Margaret Morrison Carnegie College
  - Economics
    - Industrial Economics--Annual Report, 1924-1925
    - Economics--Undergraduate Programs, 1979-1981
    - Economics--Undergraduate Programs--GSIA Relations, 1979
    - Economics--Undergraduate Programs--GSIA Relations, 1982
    - Economics--Graduate Programs, 1950-1954
    - Economics--Syllabus, 1964-1965
    - Economics, 1963-1967
    - Economics--Lecture Notes, 1917
    - Economics--GSIA, 1976-1978
    - Economics--GSIA, 1977-1980
    - Economics--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1954-1979
    - Economics--Gulf Protest, April 1970
    - Economics--Correspondence, 1979-1983
    - Economics--Memoranda, 1964-1965
    - Economics--Pamphlets, date unknown
    - Economics--Newsclippings, 1979-1983
  - English
    - English--Annual Report, 1977-1978
    - English--Annual Report, 1984
    - English--Visiting Committee Report, 1977
    - English--Visiting Committee Report, 1977[2]
    - English--Review Committee, 1987
    - English--Department Head Search, 1977-1978
    - English--Department Head Search, 1977-1978[2]
    - English--Department Head Search, 1982-1983
    - English--Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970
    - English--Undergraduate Committee Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979
    - English--Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1982-1983
    - English--Department Statistics, 1975-1985
    - English--Faculty--Courses Taught, 1955-1956
    - English--Teaching Loads, 1975-1983
    - English--Faculty List, date unknown
    - English--Promotion Criteria, 1948
    - English--Faculty Report, 1981-1982
    - English--Faculty Review Policies, 1976-1978
    - English--Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979
    - English--Eastman Review, 1974
    - English--Course Offering--C 703-4--"Materials Relating to the Teaching of Freshman Composition", 1952
    - English--Course Offerings, 1955-1956
    - English--Course Offerings, 1957
    - English--Course Offerings, 1958-1959
    - English--Course Offerings, 1962
    - English--Course Offerings, 1968-1972
    - English--Course Offerings, 1980
    - English--Course Offerings, date unknown
    - English--Steering Committee Minutes, 1969-1971
    - English--Annual Report, 1973-1974
    - English--Annual Report, 1974-1978
    - English--Annual Report, 1924-1925
    - English--Annual Report, 1925-1926
    - English--Annual Report, 1970-1971
    - English--Annual Report--Publications, 1972-1973
    - English--Annual Report--Off-Campus Activities, 1972-1973
    - English--Steering Committee Minutes, 1968-1969
    - English--Steering Committee Minutes, 1969-1970
    - English--Steering Committee Minutes, 1971-1972
    - English--Steering Committee Minutes, 1973-1974
    - English--Undergraduate Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970-1971
    - English--Undergraduate Committee Meeting Minutes, 1971-1972
    - English--Graduate Committee Minutes, 1968-1970
    - English--Graduate Committee Minutes, 1970-1971
    - English--Graduate Committee Minutes, 1972-1974
    - English--List of Lectures, 1951-1972
    - English--Lectures, 1951-1958
    - English--Lectures, 1962-1966
    - English--Lectures, 1967-1972
    - English--Newsclippings, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Correspondence, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Newsclippings and Releases, date unknown
    - Poetry on the Buses--Photos and Magazines, date unknown
    - Fred B. Millet Autobiography Series with Letter--Eliot Spencer, 1961
    - English--"Graduate Studies in English", date unknown
    - English--Annual Report--Graduate Program, 1976
    - English--Enrollment--Graduate Program, 1983
    - English--Graduate Committee Meetings, 1970
    - English--Committee for a Master’s Degree, 1962-1965
    - English--Graduate Tuition, 1977
    - English--Graduate Program--Course Offerings, 1977-1980
    - English--Master of Arts in Writing Program Proposal, date unknown
    - English--Margaret Morrison College Master of Arts Program, 1968-1969
    - English--Graduate Program--Memoranda, 1967
    - English--"The Graduate Newsletter", 1975-1982
    - English--Graduate Programs, 1986
    - English--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1981
    - English--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1982
    - English--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1983-1986
    - English--Faculty--Course Offerings Correspondence, 1976-1982
    - English--Correspondence--Curriculum, 1987
    - English--Correspondence--Wright. Austin, 1952-1961
    - English--Correspondence--Wright, Austin, 1952-1961[2]
    - English--Memoranda--Advanced Placement Program, 1961-1965
    - English--Memoranda, 1962
    - English--Memoranda, 1963
    - English--Memoranda, 1964
    - English--Memoranda, 1965
    - English--Memoranda, 1966
    - English--Memoranda, 1967
    - English--Memoranda, 1967[2]
    - English--Memoranda, 1968
    - English--Memoranda, 1968[2]
    - English--Memoranda, 1969
    - English--Memoranda, 1970
    - English--Memoranda, 1971
    - English--Memoranda, 1978-1979
    - English--Memoranda, 1981-1983
    - English--Memoranda, 1984-1986
    - English--"Tudor Rhetoric and Tudor Literature", date unknown
    - English--Waller, Gary--"Writing, Reading, Language, History, Culture", 1984
    - English--"In Honor of Austin Wright", 1972
    - English--Memoranda, 1962, 1988
    - English--The Center for the Study of Writing, date unknown
    - English--NDEA Institute Announcement, 1967
    - English--CIT Memos, 1954-1955
    - English--"Directives"--Departmental Memos, 1955
    - English--Course Regulations, 1955
    - English--Memorandum to Faculty, 1952-1953
    - English--Memorandum to Faculty, 1958-1959
    - English--Memorandum to Department Faculty, Fall 1958
    - English--Memorandum to Department Faculty, Fall 1960
    - English--Communications on Senior Electives, 1958-1959
    - English--Policy on Delinquency, 1950
    - English--Theme Regulations, 1951
    - English--Entrance Examinations for School of Applied Sciences, 1915-1927
    - English--Theme Regulations, 1951
    - English--MA--Evaluations, Outlines, Correspondence, 1962-1965
    - English--Roster of Department, 1921-1963
    - English--Benefits, Personnel Materials, 1952-1953
    - English--Faculty Bulletin, 1951-1953
    - English--Newsletter--"Discurse", April 1984
    - English--PA Council of Teachers of English--Newsletters, Correspondence, 1957-1959
    - English--Pittsburgh Association of Technical Writers--Program Minutes, 1957-1959
    - English--Professional Writing--Brochure, date unknown
    - English--Second Annual Institute of Technical Writing, 1959
    - English--Third Annual Institute of Technical Writing, 1960
    - English--Conference of English Education, 1966
    - English--"RX for Higher Education: The Doctor of Arts Degree"--Pamphlet--DA in English, 1970
    - English--Sochatoff, A. Fred--Reflects on His Years at Carnegie Mellon--by Paul R. Lyon, 1985
    - English--Wright, Austin--"Two Way Cooperation in Improving Engineering Ed"--"Victorian Bibliography for 1953", 1954
    - English--Wright, Austin--Speech--Cleeton Retirement, 1962
    - English--Swank, Earle R.--Correspondence, 1949-1958
    - English--Swank, Earle R.--National Geographic Society, date unknown
    - English--Carnegie Series in English--Correspondence, 1966-1972
    - English--Seminar--Developing Effective Communications Skills at CMU: A Look at Current Practice and New Directions, 1982
    - English--Teaching Methods to the Introduction of Literature--Reports, 1953-1958
    - English--Freshman Grades--Memorandum, 1967
    - English--Writing Clinic--Correspondence, Memoranda, 1974
    - English--Hastie, James--Self Taught Class--Report, 1969
    - English--Correspondence Collected by R. A. W., 1976-1979
    - English--"Adamson Awards"--Pamphlet, 1994
    - English--The Novel C 158--Test Questions, 1937
    - English--Conference on English Education, 1966
    - English--Graduate Studies Posters, date unknown
    - Communications Skills Center--Annual Report, 1976-1977
    - English--Report on Consulting Work, 1950-1951
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--Statements, Correspondence, 1951-1953
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--Course Handouts, 1952
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--JL Steel Corp.--Examples of Student Writing, 1951-1953
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--Pittsburgh Plate Glass--Examples of Student Writing, 1951-1953
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--Pittsburgh Plate Glass--Examples of Students Work, 1951-1953
    - English--Communications Project for Business Exec.--Pittsburgh Plate Glass--Annual Report, 1951-1952
    - English--"Needed Research in the Teaching of English"--Steinberg, 1962-1963
    - English--Advanced Placement Program--Interim Report, 1961-1962
    - English--Social Relations C 155, 1949-1950
    - English--Document Design Project, 1979
    - English--Syllabus C 703, C 704, 1951-1952
    - English--Earle Swank--Memoranda, Correspondence, Syllabi, 1950-1951
    - English--"Materials Relating to the Teaching of Freshman Composition C 703-4", 1952
    - English--English Composition C 703, C 704, 1952-1953
    - English--Composition and Literature for Architects C 727, C 7281952-1953
    - English--"Philosophical and Ethical Growths", 1955
    - English--C 170 English Seminar, 1956
    - English--English Comp. C 109, C 110, 1956
    - English--English Comp., 1958
    - English--Introduction to Literature C 728, 1956
    - English--English Composition C 703 Relating Correspondence, 1956
    - English--Introduction to Literature C 155, 1958
    - English--Carnegie Series In English, 1957-1959
    - English--Course C 156, 1958
    - English--English Composition C 703, 1958
    - English--Course 123, 1960
    - English--English Composition C 703, 1960
    - English--Nature and Function of Language C 173, 1961
    - NDEA--Institute for Advanced Study in English, 1968
    - English--Project English--Govt. Proposal, 1962
    - English--Project English--Office of Education No. 2--Statements, 1962
    - English--Project English--Abstract, June 1967
    - English--Project English--Average Students Letters Answered, 1968
    - English--Project English--Visual Machines, 1962
    - English--Project English--Correspondence, 1964
    - English--Project English--Inquiries, 1968
    - English--Project English--Form Letters, date unknown
    - English--Project English--Form Letter for Average Students, 1966
    - English--Project English--Final Report Project No. H 162, 1967
    - English--Project English--Comments by N. Hills Seniors, Final Themes, 1965
    - English--Project English--Cooperative English Tests: Form 2a--English Expression, 1960
    - English--Project English--Tests, date unknown
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Sample Selection", 1965
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Volume One: 10th Grade", 1965
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Volume Two: Eleventh Grade", 1965
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Volume Three: Twelfth Grade", 1965
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Volume Four: Grade Evaluation", 1965
    - English--Curriculum Study Center in English--"A Senior High School Curriculum In English fo Able College-Bound Students: Volume Five: Summary Report", 1965
    - English--"Project English Tenth Grade Curriculum Study: the Average Academic Student and the Teacher without Special Preparation"--Maxine N. Brandenburg, 1965